第一次每位朋友、朋友、街坊
我們所認識的每一位,早安
早安
Good morning, everyone
你知道每次都會問一個問題
今天有兩個問題要問大家
You know that I always start with a question
I have two for you today
如果問了第一個
First question
第二個可以到最後才問
So the second question will come at the end
有沒有人喜歡遊車是我的
Who like just cruising around, sightseeing, driving
你喜歡過遊車還是坐遊車
Cruising around, in the car, driving around
你舉手因為你太忙
Or maybe you don't have your hand up
because maybe you're too busy
或者你家庭生活太豐富了
Maybe you just have too many things with you
或者你根本沒有車
Maybe you don't even have a car
遊車可以是很開心的
But you know, just cruising around is actually fun
在一個小小的世界裏面只有你和我的車
Because in your own very little world, it's just you
在坐著你最喜歡的那杯咖啡
And you're just enjoying the cup of coffee
甚至乎吃著你最喜歡的那個花
Maybe you're eating your favorite bread, fun
總之走得多快也行,多慢也行
And you can drive as fast as you want
Or as slow as you want
隨著紅燈停在這裏
你喜歡轉左也行,轉右也行
When you stop at the red light
You can turn left or you can turn right
人生就是這樣多開心
If our life is like that
每天都是這樣就好了
If every day is like that
Wow, so cool
如果每天都是這樣就慘了
Oh, if every day is like that, it's so boring
9點鐘起床,就出門口
9點鐘,我走出去
兜兜兜兜兜,5點鐘回來
And just cruise around, cruise around
And then come back at 5pm
明天再來過
And it repeats
下回再來過
And then it repeats again
人生是這樣的
If our life is like that
我就叫做一個遊車河的人生
And we call it a cruising around
Or sightseeing kind of life
不知道你人生是不是這樣的呢
I'm not sure if your life is actually like that
今天我們用摩西的故事來幫我們有些反省
So today we use the story of Moses for us to reflect
摩西其實有一段人生是一個遊車河的人生
You know what, a period of Moses' life
It's actually that kind of cruising around kind of life
摩西40歲的時候
When Moses was 40 years old
他皇宮住了40年
And he was living in the palace for 40 years
我不知道怎樣形容他40年了
I don't even know how to describe the 40 years
That he was living in the palace
40年之後他就要逃去抗爺 躲起來
So after 40 years he had to escape to the wilderness
And to hide himself
我相信他從來都沒牧過羊的
I don't think he was a shepherd anyway
第40年開始就開始要過牧羊的生活
So 40th year he had to be a shepherd
每天帶著羊咩出去逛街
And every day he had to take the sheep out
我想他第一天去真的很開心的
Maybe the first day he was quite happy
沒有人跟他爭辯
Because nobody is going to argue with him
Nobody is going to fight with him for anything
每天都是說著同一樣的東西
Every day he said the same thing
咩咩咩咩咩
哇 多開心
哇哇哇 多開心
全部都認同
And everybody agrees with him
每天都很開心 都不會說紙
Every day they are so happy
每天都這樣 多好
Every day is like that
一個星期一年兩年過了
One week, a month, a year passed
都是這樣的
It's still the same thing
咩咩咩咩咩
咩咩咩 吧啦吧啦吧啦
你們全部都在咩咩咩
So everybody is like what 吧啦吧啦
我又叫過
當前面沒有車
又叫遊車我人生
叫遊牧人生
So we cannot call it that
A cruising around Cascadia
Have a carbon
Maybe a nomadic life
每日都遊下遊下過日子
Every day he just goes and cruise around
四十年之後當他八十歲的時候
Forty years after when he was eighty years old
就是今天讀了經文才開始
It is the beginning of the passage that we have today
終於遇見到神了
He finally experienced God and encountered God
今日就希望用摩西人生的一些經歷
So today we would like to look at the experiences that Moses had
幫助我自己做的一些反省
To help myself to reflect on the things that happened in my life
又或者同你人生一些的反省
Maybe it would be also relevant to your life
數下數下其實我係教會侍奉到啱啱好又係四十年喎
So as I count my fingers
I actually have been serving the longer forty years
唔知係咩咩咩呢即係點樣呢
You don't know it's forty years of past
我嘗試將過去四十年的侍奉人生
分開六個階段來同大家分享
So I would like to share with you my past forty years of serving life
and into six different periods
第一個階段我叫做相信神係有預備嘅階段
So the first period is that I trusted God's provision
就係正係我自己不知不覺中睇唔到神預備嘅階段
And it was actually without my knowing that it just happened
God's provision just happened
我都係喺個階段喺皇宮裏面學咗皇宮裏面嘅禮儀
So Moses learned all the etiquette in the palace
佢知道點樣同你皇宮裏面知人哋要交往
He knew how to interact with the people inside
神就意味咗佢呢個咁嘅背景
And so God has prepared him with that kind of background
跟住佢四十到八十歲嗰時就咩咩咩嘅階段
佢就開始由衝動嘅人生變成一個唔多講嘢嘅人生
So Moses from forty to eighty
He started with the shepherding life
and into a more quieting
神將佢嘅心收起上嚟
So God kind of hid his heart from Moses
變成一個唔多識講嘢嘅模式
So Moses turned into a person who is not very eloquent
但神又為佢預備一個哥哥
But God prepared a big brother for Moses
佢係個識講嘢嘅口才嘅哥哥幫佢
God has prepared a big brother who is very talkative
or who is very eloquent to help him
係呀,話返我自己
And so when I looked at myself
我十九歲嘅時候
When I was nineteen years old
未曾認識神
I didn't know God yet
只係識讀書,返學識女朋友,拍多開心玩
So I studied, I went to work, I got a girlfriend
and just had fun
其實都幾開心嘅
I was pretty happy
當時嘅我唔知道自己過緊一個
遊車海人生嘅家庭
I didn't know that I was actually living
just a cruising sightseeing kind of life
但神又為我預備了
But God has prepared for me
神為我預備一個非常好嘅知己
God has prepared me a very close friend
非常好嘅知己
A very good companion
當時冇諗過佢成為人生嘅知己
I didn't know that that person
would become my closest companion of my life
更加重要嘅
But more importantly
佢係令裏面嗰個同行者
She was walking with me in spiritual life
一齊信主 一齊守禁
一齊去侍奉人生嘅伴侶
We got to accept Christ together
We went to church together
We got baptized together
We got to serving together
我相信神都為我哋每一個人
要預備一個伴侶
I believe that God prepared
a companion for each person
唔一定係家庭裏面嘅伴侶
It doesn't have to be a spouse or family
可以係侍奉裏面嘅伴侶
They can be partners in service
佢侍奉裏面嘅同工
It can be co-workers in life
或者係工作崗位裏面一個同志
Maybe a colleague at work
同你一齊行呢條嘅人生路
That they would journey with you
一齊經歷因典嘅人生路
They would experience grace of God together with you
好快再去到第二個人生階段
And we're going to the second period
第二個階段我叫做
清楚知道神嘅召命嘅階段
The second period of time
I would call it that I know God's calling quite clearly
其實摩西係一個好有心嘅人
You know, Moses has a heart
Very caring, very loving
佢愛佢啲同胞
He loves his own people
為咗同胞甚至殺咗一個埃及人
Because of his own people
He actually killed an Egyptian
為咗啲同胞佢可以留落喺曠野幾十年
Because of his own people
He would stay in the wilderness for a few decades
但係喺四十到八十歲呢啲時間
我相信佢不斷等候緊一個嘅時間
But within 40 years or in 18 years, I believe that he was waiting for an opportunity
等陣究竟神要帶領佢去邊一個嘅階段
Waiting? How God is going to lead him?
佢淨係知道佢嘅祖宗有一個神
He knew that his ancestors had a God
好震撼
當佢見到一個燒著嘅荊棘嘅時候
When he saw the burning bush
佢有好多種嘅反應
He had a lot of reactions
佢可以選擇
I mean he had a lot of reactions to choose
火燒樹有咩未見過啫
A bush in fire, have you seen it?
睇到,咪當睇唔到,繼續目佢啲羊囉
Well, he could choose to not see it
咩咩咩,我哋走啦,冇嘢睇
He's like, oh, we should go, let's go
但佢見到一個神跡
But he saw a miracle
佢知道呢樣嘢係不尋常嘅
It's extraordinary, he knew it
He knew that you don't see this kind of things everyday
He's very curious
佢驚驚兩點說佢回頭睇下究竟發生咗乜嘢事
So the scripture said Moses turned around to see what's going on
就係因為呢個回頭睇好奇嘅動作
It's because of that he turned around
神就繼續同摩西講說話
God continued to speak to Moses
神就繼續將佢親父佢嘅照明交落去摩西
God continued to reveal his heart and his calling to Moses
第二階段我去到29歲啦
The second period I was 29 years old
我信了耶穌後冇幾耐
I just accepted Christ a little bit at that time
當時前嘅導師教咗我哋呢
信咗耶穌後返教會要喺教會裡面侍奉㗎嘛
So our fellowship counselor taught us that
Once we accept Christ, we are to serve God in church
我都同大家一樣係一個好乖嘅學生
And I'm quite obedient
當時就諗啦
So I was thinking
佢話聖經唔係咁熟
I'm not very familiar with scripture
當時教會冇幾耐
So I've been at the church for a little while
有啲咩可以侍奉呢
What can I do to serve him?
當時教會有一個侍奉係喺
多倫多東邊一個鎮做一啲嘅海外學生工作
So it was at the east side of the church
We were doing some student work
當時我嚟咗加拿大只係兩三年嘅時間
I was only in Canada for like two to three years
做學生香港嚟嘅學生工作就好適合啦
So dealing with people from Hong Kong
Students from Hong Kong doing ministering to them
It's very suitable
我雖然唔識教聖經
Even though I didn't know how to teach the Bible
又唔識解決嗰啲問題
佢啲學生我問佢好多次頑皮嘅問題
I might not even be able to solve any problems
但可以跟住啲神
喺主義裏面嘅哥哥姐姐去學習
點樣帶領口侶
But I can actually follow the big brothers
and big sisters of the church
I can learn from them how to have discussion
and a conversation
好快就呢
當時嘅武會係北約華人信信會
So my mother church is
North York Chinese Baptist Church
武會當時係直堂
And they were planting a church
直堂喺麗明山
They were planting a church up to Richmond Hill
今日嘅麗明山
So the R.H.C. Richmond Hill Chinese Baptist today
我又諗啦
So I was thinking
約新信徒
A new believer
乜嘢都唔識
Doesn't know anything
跟住直堂有咩好做呢
During the church planting
What can I do during the church planting
我就抱咗一個好簡單嘅心
A very simple heart that I have
120個人
We had 120 people
有118個人知道嘅意思做乜
Maybe there is 118 people
Who knew what they were doing
Who didn't know
其實我哋嗰兩個唔知
So the two who left behind
Didn't know what we were doing
佢就好放心
跟住去咗直堂
And so we were so relaxed
And then we just followed
跟住去直堂就容易啦
And it's easy
You just follow
跟住去直堂就做乜呀
So what do we do after
We planted the church
當時嚟咗移民都係兩三年嘅時間
I was only in Canada for 2-3 years
英文就麻麻地
My English wasn't that good
我媽媽地都可以教下嘢嘅
But I could teach a little bit
我又唔係教英文
But of course I wasn't teaching English
教聖經和英語
But I was actually started to
Teach a Bible
但係唔可以教大人呀
Of course I couldn't teach adults
全部都係啲哥哥姐姐
It's all big brothers big sisters
所以當時幫手教嗰啲五六年班嘅細路仔
So I was teaching the grade 5s and the grade 6s
起碼佢問啲問題冇咁深
You know the questions wouldn't be that hard
咁開始咗呢個照明嘅人生
So I started the life of calling
體會就係唔好輕看每一個侍奉嘅機會
The thing is we don't look at
All the opportunities of serving very likely
我發展到第三階段
Let's go into the third period
就係點樣配合第一階段每人嘅calling
嚟到去參與侍奉
I call it how do I participate in unity
With the brothers and sisters
摩西都經歷咗同一樣嘅掙扎
Moses was also struggling
喺我哋生活中摩西係一個問好多問題嘅人
In our minds maybe Moses had a lot of questions
神叫佢去做嘢佢唔係去做
佢唔係行到度問問題
So when God called him to do something
He didn't just do it
He kept asking questions
我係邊個?我點做呢啲嘢呀?
Who am I? How can I do this?
神就要答佢囉
So God answered him
咁你邊個?你乜嘢神嚟㗎?
And he answered, he said, "Who are you, right?"
咁如果啲人唔信我咁點算呀?
And he said, "I told the people about you
but they didn't believe, what do I do?"
去到埃及王嗰度我點知講啲乜嘢好呀?
When I go to Pharaoh, what should I say?
我係唔識講嘢嘅人
你識咩咩咩點可以帶啲人做呢樣嘢呢?
I'm not eloquent, I don't know how to speak
神就一一嘅回答
So God responded to him one by one
最後摩西有冇做到呀?
After all, did Moses do what he was called to do?
喺做咗之前你仲講咗一句說話
Before he started doing that, he said this
你可唔可以搞我呀?我搵帝哥啦不如
Oh
你不如搵帝哥啦,唔好搵我
Don't bother me, just find someone else
有乜嘢好熟悉嘅嘢都講個類似說話係咪?
Did Jesus also say something like this?
如果呢個虎杯可以拎開嘅,就拎開
但我願意順服神你自己
You can take the cup from me, please do
可唔可以話,可唔可以搵帝哥,唔好搵我呀?
But I'll do whatever you say
So the thing is, can God find someone else?
神就偏偏要搵佢
But God deliberately wanted Moses
攞住佢畀你手,讓佢行神職,完成我個使命
So take this cup and go and fulfill my calling for you
我自己都去到39歲嘅時候
When I became 39 years old
跟住食堂咗十年啦
It was about 10 years after church planting
食堂咗十年之後,你跟住有咩好做呀?
So after 10 years, what do I do?
真係,食堂咗十年之後
就要建堂啦嘛,好似我哋咁嘛
So it's actually after the church was planted
10 years after that
It was another opportunity to plant another church
當時我就參與過建堂小組呀
嗰啲委員會呀嗰啲嘅工作
So I was actually involved in a church planting group
同一時間呢,教堂其實好多嘢做㗎
A church building group, as I said
There is a lot of things to do within this church building
去咗建堂之後仲有好多嘢做㗎嘛
Besides the building, the church, there are also a lot of places and things to do
當時我就做咗英文堂嘅執事
So I became an ESC deacon
又喺英文堂度教嗰啲小朋友
So within the English speaking congregation
I continued to teach the children and teens
但係嗰個時候神就感動我去教啲中文嘅小朋友
So God at that time has moved me to teach the Cantonese speaking kids
當時教堂其實係冇廣東話嘅青少年子宮嘅
At that time we didn't really have a Cantonese speaking teenage fellowship
or youth fellowship
我就好似摩西可以掙扎啦
So I was like Moses, I was struggling
做邊樣好呢
What should I do? What do I do?
咁多嘢做唔曬呀
Of course I cannot do it all
繼續做執事呀
Should I continue to be a deacon?
做執事加埋英文堂嘅侍奉呀
A deacon with the English speaking congregation ministries?
做執事繼續教英文嗰啲小朋友呀
Maybe to continue to be a deacon and continue to teach the kids?
或者做執事去教廣東話嘅小朋友呢
Or to be a deacon and teach Cantonese speaking kids?
嗰時神就感動我去選擇做咗英文同埋中文嘅青少年工作
So God has moved me to choose to minister
To both English speaking and Cantonese speaking kids and youth
就擺低咗執事嘅侍奉
And to put down the deacon ministry
一時見我叫佢去做開心參與
適應住教會需要嚟叫佢去侍奉
So I call it a joyfully engaged into this calling-driven life
隨住教會發展嘅需要唔係唔同
With the developments of the church
我哋隨住嚟到去改變同埋適應神畀我哋嘅感動
With how God is leading the church, we just follow His guidance
重返咗去到第四個人生階段
And very quickly we went to the fourth period
第四個嘅奉職階段
The fourth ministry period
就係願意繼續接受造就嘅階段
I continue to be willing to be equipped for ministries
摩西大地西利亞都擴建咗佢哋嗰個幾十年嘅時間
So God was using Moses to lead the Israelites in the New Orleans for a few decades
有個位好特別嘅
There was a time, it's very special
摩西係嗰個領導
So Moses was the leader
以色列人排咗隊去見佢
And Israelites were lining up to see him
忙到佢真係不得了
He was so busy
以色列人要由朝排到晚去見一見摩西
睇下神嘅心意
The Israelites were lining up from daytime to nighttime to see Moses
To see the heart of God, to see the will of God
喺嗰陣時神就直住佢
佢就提醒佢
But God has used Moses' father-in-law to remind him
你咁樣做法唔掂㗎喎
I mean... I mean...
Moses, you cannot do that
咁樣排法搞唔掂㗎你
You cannot have all the people lining up to see you
你嗰次啲法寶長、師父長嚟做管治嘅政客
You got to have people to help you out
留返啲真係好大件事先問你啦
Just leave the big problems to you
摩西當時係幾百萬人嘅領導
You know, he was the leader for millions, couple of millions of people
就願意聽一個老人家嘅勸勉勤誠
That he was willing to listen to an older person
願意學習去改變、去服侍神
He was willing to change, to obey God, to serve God
當我49歲嗰時
When I was 49 years old
佢教會咗侍奉佢都一年嘅時間
And so it's been a while that I've been serving a church
黎明山殿堂直堂就完成咗
So the church building for RCBC was done
黎明山就有新嘅動向
And there was a new development from RCBC
當教會一路長大時候有咩可以做呀?
When the church kept growing, what do you do?
直堂
To plant a church this time after you built the church
黎明山教會有直堂
So RCBC started to want to plant a church
神就感動我哋今次參與直堂
So God has moved us to be involved in this church planting project
The second time of church planting
上一次就跟住18個人去
The first time we were following 118 people
今次神要我哋帶住60幾人去
This time God asked us to take about 60 people
好緊張嘅
It's very nervous
真係喺人哋後面行嘅好容易
When I was following somebody, it was pretty relaxing
然後我哋帶住前面
帶二人、六十幾人喺後面行嘅好難
Then I was one of the leaders in the front
leading 60 something people
It was kind of a wrecking
剛才頭先舉手話喺初代有份參與嘅嘢
你哋好爽呀
So the people who were here
that also came from RCBC
you probably felt quite relaxed as well
前面有兩個
哥哥、弟姐好似我同Karen
帶住你行呀
Because there are two big brothers and sisters
like myself and Karen to lead
不過唔使驚
But don't fear
神話我必與你同去
God said I will go with you
同一時間神就俾我另一個感動
So God has touched me again
唔單止要侍奉
It's not just to serve
仲要去神學院接受訓練
But to be equipped in the seminary
我已經喺教會侍奉咗咁多年
仲要受訓練
But I have been serving at church for many years
I still need to be equipped
神就感動我
So God has touched me
呢個故事你而家會以前聽過
即使知道唔聽過都唔緊要
So there's another story
You might have heard it in God
總之就係喺不熱議嘅裏面
就願意去參與呢個行動
就去神學院接受訓練
So it's like struggling in between
Should I go? Should I not go?
呢個叫做虛心學習嘅少年人生階段
I call it a calling driven life
that is marked by humble learning
好快就去到第五個階段
So really quickly we go into the fifth period
我叫做金心存然擺上嘅教美人生階段
I call it a wholehearted offering to God
摩西金心去服侍神
帶領伊斯里人去到咩地步呢
Moses had no reserve
and continued to serve God
to what extent
神本來要懲罰伊斯里人
因為佢哋犯罪得罪神
God was going to punish the Israelites
because they sinned against God
摩西求情而然要呈獻佢自己嘅靈智
喺神嘅冊子上面逃去
都要為伊斯里民求神延殊
Moses was actually willing to have his name blotted out
and to beg for God's blessings for his own people
佢然然為佢所愛嘅伊斯里民族犧牲
到咗呢個地步
He was willing to sacrifice himself
for the people he loved, his own people
去到我59歲嘅時候
when I was 59 years old
我都冇摩西咁嘅心情
I don't think I have the heart of Moses
佢個心好大我個心好細
His heart is big but my heart is little
我所能夠付上嘅我唔會
都唔能夠將我自己喺神裏面嗰份名份攞走
I don't think I can sacrifice like Moses
第二張我所能夠俾教會就俾咗教會
But whatever I can to my best capability
I give to church and to God
我能夠做嘅就係作為一個義務嘅牧者
讓教會將有限嘅資源
並且要聘請更加多嘅牧者幫助教會
What I could do is that I become a volunteer pastor
and to leave the resources to hire other pastors
我心意就係幫助我所愛嘅教會
去建造人
建造一個神嘅殿
My hope and my wish is that
to have the resources to build God's people
and to build God's building
十年前頭先話十年前我哋買咗呢幅地
So we mentioned that this piece of land
was purchased ten years ago
當時我哋只係得七十八十人度
We only had about 70 to 80 people at that time
能俾我哋又去建堂嘅心願
But God has given us the vision to build a church
俾我哋有信心去完成呢個使命
He has given us faith to continue to do so
當時呢幅地六十幾萬買返嚟
So it's about six hundred thousand dollars
而家呢去到二百幾萬
And now it's like two million dollars
如果當時信心唔夠呢
今日可能買唔到
So if we didn't have the faith
we couldn't have bought this piece of land
我叫呢個階段係全心全意擺上嘅
照命人生階段
I call it is a wholehearted offering
in this calling driven life
我快啲去到第六個階段
Very quickly it's come to the sixth life period
我叫佢一個視同同埋參與
唔會退避嘅人生視同階段
I would call it a period
that I served without retreat
摩西喺國人入面帶咗伊斯蘭人四十年
So Moses had led the Israelites for forty years
終於去到英去之地嘅門口
Finally they have come to the entrance of the promised land
佢嘅使命係完成咗
He had accomplished his mission
你可能問
過去呢四十年八十到一百二十歲
Moses 四十年係一個乜嘢嘅人生
From when Moses was 80 years old to 120 years old
What kind of life was that?
話佢係一個照命人生四十年嘅居留
If you call it a calling driven life
Please raise your hand
Moses 係咁嘅
I'm talking about Moses of course
總之其他人都覺得佢唔係
Maybe the others don't really think
that it was a calling driven life
佢可能懷疑佢係咪過緊一個遊車可人生
Maybe he went back to be like a cruising kind of life
四十年佢帶住啲羊咩
佢就咩咩咩咗四十年
Forty years she was bringing sheep
跟住嗰四十年佢帶住呢四年又嗌過
抗議佢成又又又又又又好四十年
The second forty years he led the Israelites
also wandering around
係咪你有咩分別呀
What was the difference to him? What do you think?
帶住羊咩四十年好似浪費咗好多個時間
When you take care of the sheep
It seems like that he's wasted many years
養大咗就湯 養大咗就賣 養大咗就湯
So when they become bigger and then you just kill it
And then you sell it and it repeats again and again
帶住羊咩四十年又點樣呢
But when you take the Israelites for forty years
What do you do?
好似冇方向喺度抗議佢哋游呀游呀游呀游呀
It seems like that you have no direction
In the wilderness it's also wandering around
行呀停呀 行呀停呀 停四十年喇
And when you like you walk a little bit and you stop
And you walk a little bit for forty years
咁樣係唔係一個游木
或者尤其係我人生係一個善明照明嘅人生呢
Is it a nomadic life? Is it a cruising kind of life?
Is it a calling trip in life?
大家睇唔睇到個區別喺邊度呀
Do you see the difference?
羊咩唔會越嚟越靈裏面成長㗎
For the sheep they actually they won't grow spiritually
佢即係越嚟越大隻俾人劏嘅人
They would grow bigger in size and they would get killed
佢哋啲民族係越嚟越能夠明白神
願意親近神 依靠神 遵守神
But for Israelites they actually learned
They actually matured
They actually started to know God better
They obeyed God better
佢四十年嘅照明就係摩西大地之人成長嘅家園
So those forty years actually Moses led the Israelites
in a growth and maturity period
終於去到令去之地嘅門口準備入去
And they have come to the entrance to the promised land
對我嚟咗就去到69歲
So to me is 69 years old
今年我就69歲
So I'm turning 69 this year
我嘅人生又係點樣嘅呢
What is my life going to be like?
同大家一齊喺呢個地方建造一個封印嘅基地
We are together building a foundation of Christ here
for the Gospels
我好知道要相信呢個基地
係需要我哋每一位嘅參與先能夠成事
I deeply know and I deeply believe
that only with every single person's participation
that this project would be accomplished
呢啲問題全部去咗四十年之後
一齊加難
The Israelites went into the promised land together
唔值得入去嗰啲又唔會得入去
For those God did say not to go in
They didn't have a chance to go in
希望呢度每一個都能夠去到呢個封印嘅基地
進入呢個封印嘅基地
I pray that everyone will be able to come into
this Gospel headquarters
所以每一個人參與先成事
So we need everyone's participation and involvement
我同我一家喺六月份嘅時候
已經見到一份動員嘅表格
My family and I all did the Pledge for in June
你做咗你個份未呢
Have you done your part
你又做咗你個份未呢
最後問大家一個問題
My second question today
我深信過去四十年前
帶領我哋過咗一個照明人生嘅階段
I believe that after like forty years
It was a calling driven life
因為我哋一路都係有我願意
侍奉參與嘅心
Because we want to
We are willing to participate in serving God together
憑住信心依靠神嚟到個國每一步
And only by grace God's grace and faith
That we can live everyday
第二個問題問大家嘅
The second question that I am going to ask
你哋願唔願意過一個照明人生
係甘心嘅去侍奉參與同埋動員嘅大作
Are you willing to live a calling driven life
wholeheartedly offering to God
humbly learning and giving glory to God
呢個問題大家要答嘅
This question I want you to answer
我哋問一次囉
Let me ask you once again
你願唔願意甘心樂意去侍奉參與同埋動員
Are you willing to offer yourself
to make sacrifice to participate in serving God
and to partner with one another together
願意嘅舉手
If you are willing raise your hand
我見到仲有啲好含蓄
A little shy
我知點解
That's ok
因為我講得太細聲
Oh, yeah, because I was too shocked
我再問一次
I'll ask again
你哋係咪甘心樂意去過一個
願意侍奉參與同埋供應嘅照明人生
Are you willing to live a life of politics
wholeheartedly, humbly learning
enjoy participating together
Please, the Lord
最後一個結論
Last
上個禮拜我哋嘅Missionary Wendy同我哋講
我哋要開你哋要開你哋要開你記得嗎
So last week Missionary Wendy told us
You go, go, go
我又講埋下一段
So I said the second part of it
我哋要出去傳福音 啱嘅
We go to spread the gospel
That's correct
我哋要出去又要招再返起
But when we go, we get scattered
We have to gather again
我哋招再返起又要再出去
When we scatter, we gather
and we go be scattered again
最後送畀大家呢一句
同聖經裡面講嘅說話
The last one that I would like to share with you is
from the Bible itself
記得當時摩西見到神
神同佢講過咩說話
So when Moses met God, God told him this
神畀摩西嘅叫命係乜嘢
What is the mission that God gave Moses
佢同摩西講佢話你而家要去呀
He said to Moses, now you go
我要差你去到塊路嗰度
I'm sending you to Pharaoh
將我嘅百姓以色列人喺埃及大力出嚟
To bring my people, the Israelites, out of Egypt
做乜嘢呀
To do what
嚟到摩西完成呢個山嚟到敬拜神呀
To worship God
今日畀我哋忍前咁對每一個人
嘅吩咐嘅叫命喺呢度
So that's the calling for us SGBC
Each and everyone here as a church as a whole
而家我哋要去呀
Now we go
能要差拜我哋要去到社區人群嗰度
Because the Lord is sending us to go into the community
將屬於神屬於主嘅人帶你出嚟
To bring the people of God
嚟到呢個地方一齊嚟到敬拜神
To go and worship God together
喺呢個神所俾我哋嘅地方
At this place that God's given us
聚埋一齊之後唔喺度享樂呀
But we're not just having fun after we gather
聚咗埋一齊我哋就更加大手
我就可以再出去再將神嘅福音去得更遠更廣
It's when we gather we have the strength
And to be scattered again
And to spread His truth and love
呢個係我哋今生試訓嘅照明人生嘅結果
That is the result of a calling driven life
因傳喺呢個地方建立成就嘅結果
And that's the purpose of SGBC building a church here
我真係用心祈禱
Let's pray
天上多謝你俾我呢幅咁美麗嘅地方
Father God thank you for this beautiful piece of land
要我哋唔係喺度欣賞呢個美麗
You're not asking us to just appreciate how pretty it is
又係大大嘅嘢嚟到使用
But you have commanded us to use it
成為我真正福音嘅基地
To make it a gospel headquarter
喺呢度聚集
To gather here
喺呢度出去
And to be scattered from here
去到唔同嘅地方
To go to different places
唔同嘅人群嘅裏面
To different communities
係要成就神祢自己嘅心意
And accomplish your will
多謝你嘅照明
God thank you for your calling for us
同你交代俾我哋每一個
May you give strength to us
俾我哋嘅心全部連起喺一齊
May you bind our hearts all together
成就你嘅照明
To accomplish your calling
多謝你聽我祈禱
Thank you for listening to our prayers
耶穌基督得勝你名禁
In Jesus name we pray
Amen